{
  "questionList": {
    "question1": [
      {
        "id": 1,
        "question": "In which month of 1914 did the First World War begin?",
        "option1": "May",
        "option2": "June",
        "option3": "July",
        "answer": "July"
      },
      {
        "id": 2,
        "question": "In what year was the Russian Revolution?",
        "option1": "1917",
        "option2": "1918",
        "option3": "1918",
        "answer": "1918"
      },
      {
        "id": 3,
        "question": "Which Roman emperor declared war on Neptune, God of the sea?",
        "option1": "Caligula",
        "option2": "Robert",
        "option3": "Thomas",
        "answer": "Caligula"
      },
      {
        "id": 4,
        "question": "Who assassinated Abraham Lincoln?",
        "option1": "James Williamson",
        "option2": "John Wilkes Booth",
        "option3": "Peter Fred",
        "answer": "John Wilkes Booth"
      },
      {
        "id": 5,
        "question": "Who became the Prime Minister of UK in 2022?",
        "option1": "Rishi Sunak",
        "option2": "Toni Blair",
        "option3": "Charles",
        "answer": "Rishi Sunak"
      },
      {
        "id": 6,
        "question": "Who was the world’s first woman Prime Minister?",
        "option1": "Sirimavo Bandaranaike",
        "option2": "Indira Gandhi",
        "option3": "Golda Meir",
        "answer": "Sirimavo Bandaranaike"
      },
      {
        "id": 7,
        "question": "Who became Prime Minister of Britain in 1916?",
        "option1": "Woodrow Wilson",
        "option2": "Georges Clemenceau",
        "option3": "David Lloyd George",
        "answer": "David Lloyd George"
      },
      {
        "id": 8,
        "question": "Which is the highest mountain in the world?",
        "option1": "Mount Everest",
        "option2": "Cuzco",
        "option3": "Mercedario",
        "answer": "Mount Everest"
      },
      {
        "id": 9,
        "question": "What year was the golden age of piracy?",
        "option1": "1630 - 1750s",
        "option2": "1560 - 1630s",
        "option3": "1650 - 1730s",
        "answer": "1650 - 1730s"
      },
      {
        "id": 10,
        "question": "Which member of the British royal family was murdered by the IRA in 1979?",
        "option1": "Lord Mountbatten",
        "option2": "King George I",
        "option3": "King James VI",
        "answer": "Lord Mountbatten"
      },
      {
        "id": 11,
        "question": "Whose death sparked World War I?",
        "option1": "Kaiser Wilhelm",
        "option2": "Queen Victoria",
        "option3": "Archduke Franz Ferdinand",
        "answer": "Archduke Franz Ferdinand"
      },
      {
        "id": 12,
        "question": "Which of these nations was neutral in World War I?",
        "option1": "Germany",
        "option2": "Norway",
        "option3": "Italy",
        "answer": "Norway"
      },
      {
        "id": 13,
        "question": "Which of these ships was sunk by a German submarine?",
        "option1": "Titanic",
        "option2": "Arizona",
        "option3": "Lusitania",
        "answer": "Lusitania"
      },
      {
        "id": 14,
        "question": "How many republics made up the former Soviet Union?",
        "option1": "15",
        "option2": "12",
        "option3": "20",
        "answer": "15"
      },
      {
        "id": 15,
        "question": "When was the first Nobel Prize in economics awarded?",
        "option1": "1929",
        "option2": "1949",
        "option3": "1969",
        "answer": "1969"
      },
      {
        "id": 16,
        "question": "Which Indian president was involved in the struggle for Irish independence?",
        "option1": "Neelam Sanjiva Reddy",
        "option2": "V.V. Giri",
        "option3": "S. Radhakrishnan",
        "answer": "V.V. Giri"
      },
      {
        "id": 17,
        "question": "Where were the Aegean Bronze Age civilizations located?",
        "option1": "Greece",
        "option2": "Spain",
        "option3": "India",
        "answer": "Greece"
      },
      {
        "id": 18,
        "question": "Who was the first U.S. president to appear on television?",
        "option1": "Richard Nixon",
        "option2": "Ronald Reagan",
        "option3": "Franklin Delano Roosevelt",
        "answer": "Franklin Delano Roosevelt"
      },
      {
        "id": 19,
        "question": "In what American state would you find Denali?",
        "option1": "Alabama",
        "option2": "Alaska",
        "option3": "Arizona",
        "answer": "Alaska"
      },
      {
        "id": 20,
        "question": "Which state seceded from Virginia in 1863?",
        "option1": "West Virginia",
        "option2": "Maryland",
        "option3": "North Carolina",
        "answer": "West Virginia"
      },
      {
        "id": 21,
        "question": "What is the capital of Illinois?",
        "option1": "Streator",
        "option2": "Urbana",
        "option3": "Springfield",
        "answer": "Springfield"
      },
      {
        "id": 22,
        "question": "How many kings of England have been named Henry?",
        "option1": "8",
        "option2": "12",
        "option3": "14",
        "answer": "8"
      },
      {
        "id": 23,
        "question": "Which king signed the Magna Carta?",
        "option1": "James",
        "option2": "William",
        "option3": "John",
        "answer": "John"
      },
      {
        "id": 24,
        "question": "Which Egyptian pharaoh believed in the idea of a single god?",
        "option1": "Cheops",
        "option2": "Akhenaton",
        "option3": "Nefertiti",
        "answer": "Akhenaton"
      },
      {
        "id": 25,
        "question": "Which of these was an Egyptian king?",
        "option1": "Farouk",
        "option2": "Zog",
        "option3": "Andrew",
        "answer": "Farouk"
      },
      {
        "id": 26,
        "question": "How long did Hitler envision his Third Reich lasting?",
        "option1": "100 years",
        "option2": "1000 years",
        "option3": "50 years",
        "answer": "1000 years"
      },
      {
        "id": 27,
        "question": "What style of architecture is exemplified by the Notre Dame cathedral in Paris?",
        "option1": "Art Deco",
        "option2": "Brutalist",
        "option3": "Gothic",
        "answer": "Gothic"
      },
      {
        "id": 28,
        "question": "Where was the Metric System developed?",
        "option1": "Italy",
        "option2": "France",
        "option3": "USA",
        "answer": "France"
      },
      {
        "id": 29,
        "question": "In what modern-day country was Stalin born?",
        "option1": "Russia",
        "option2": "Germany",
        "option3": "Georgia",
        "answer": "Georgia"
      },
      {
        "id": 30,
        "question": "When did the Crimean War happen?",
        "option1": "1800s",
        "option2": "1700s",
        "option3": "1900s",
        "answer": "1800s"
      },
      {
        "id": 31,
        "question": "Who did John Hinckley shoot in 1981?",
        "option1": "Golda Meir",
        "option2": "John Lennon",
        "option3": "Ronald Reagan",
        "answer": "Ronald Reagan"
      },
      {
        "id": 32,
        "question": "What term refers to a branch of a royal family founded by younger sons?",
        "option1": "Cadet branch",
        "option2": "Ensign branch",
        "option3": "Lieutenant branch",
        "answer": "Cadet branch"
      },
      {
        "id": 33,
        "question": "What did Wernher von Braun design?",
        "option1": "Furniture",
        "option2": "Rockets",
        "option3": "Clothing",
        "answer": "Rockets"
      },
      {
        "id": 34,
        "question": "Who hosted the Olympics in 1940?",
        "option1": "Paris",
        "option2": "Los Angeles",
        "option3": "Cancelled",
        "answer": "Cancelled"
      },
      {
        "id": 35,
        "question": "What country accepted responsibility for the bombing of Pan Am Flight 103 over Lockerbie, Scotland?",
        "option1": "Russia",
        "option2": "Libya",
        "option3": "North Korea",
        "answer": "Libya"
      },
      {
        "id": 36,
        "question": "What was the original purpose of the Taj Mahal?",
        "option1": "A mausoleum",
        "option2": "An armory",
        "option3": "A mosque",
        "answer": "A mausoleum"
      },
      {
        "id": 37,
        "question": "What was the capital of the Byzantine Empire?",
        "option1": "Constantinople",
        "option2": "Rome",
        "option3": "Jerusalem",
        "answer": "Constantinople"
      },
      {
        "id": 38,
        "question": "What did Costa Rica abolish in 1949?",
        "option1": "Taxes",
        "option2": "Slavery",
        "option3": "Its military",
        "answer": "Its military"
      },
      {
        "id": 39,
        "question": "Which of these crops DIDN'T come from the New World?",
        "option1": "Hemp",
        "option2": "Tomatoes",
        "option3": "Maize",
        "answer": "Hemp"
      },
      {
        "id": 40,
        "question": "Where did Karl Marx spend most of his adult life?",
        "option1": "Berlin",
        "option2": "Moscow",
        "option3": "London",
        "answer": "London"
      },
      {
        "id": 41,
        "question": "What country was formerly known as Southern Rhodesia?",
        "option1": "Uruguay",
        "option2": "Zimbabwe",
        "option3": "Kenya",
        "answer": "Zimbabwe"
      },
      {
        "id": 42,
        "question": "Which of these countries was never colonized in any way by France?",
        "option1": "Chile",
        "option2": "Vietnam",
        "option3": "Algeria",
        "answer": "Chile"
      },
      {
        "id": 43,
        "question": "Which of these years occurred during the Belle Époque?",
        "option1": "1750",
        "option2": "1900",
        "option3": "1600",
        "answer": "1900"
      },
      {
        "id": 44,
        "question": "Which of these was invented in France?",
        "option1": "Airplanes",
        "option2": "Computers",
        "option3": "Photography",
        "answer": "Photography"
      },
      {
        "id": 45,
        "question": "What is the name of the current iteration of the French government?",
        "option1": "Second Republic",
        "option2": "Fifth Republic",
        "option3": "Third Republic",
        "answer": "Fifth Republic"
      },
      {
        "id": 46,
        "question": "In which war did France suffer the most military casualties?",
        "option1": "World War One",
        "option2": "Algerian War",
        "option3": "World War Two",
        "answer": "World War One"
      },
      {
        "id": 47,
        "question": "Who were the Huguenots?",
        "option1": "Early hot air balloon explorers",
        "option2": "French Protestants",
        "option3": "Fans of Victor Hugo",
        "answer": "French Protestants"
      },
      {
        "id": 48,
        "question": "What country was blamed for the sinking of the USS Maine in 1898?",
        "option1": "Spain",
        "option2": "Germany",
        "option3": "UK",
        "answer": "Spain"
      },
      {
        "id": 49,
        "question": "In what year did the U.S enter World War II?",
        "option1": "1939",
        "option2": "1941",
        "option3": "1944",
        "answer": "1941"
      },
      {
        "id": 50,
        "question": "Which of these cities has not hosted the Olympics?",
        "option1": "St. Louis",
        "option2": "Chicago",
        "option3": "Atlanta",
        "answer": "Chicago"
      }
    ]
  }
}
